Apurva Tripathi

403, Park Avenue, Mahalaxmi Soc., Chala, Daman Rd., Vapi, Gujarat (396191) (C) +919624880002 | (H) +912602460158 | apurvatripathi13@gmail.com

http://aptr13.me | https://www.linkedin.com/in/aptr13 | https://github.com/ApTr13

Professional Summary

Experienced Full Stack Web developer with an ambitious vision of working in the information technology and services industry. Nanodegree Graduate in Full Stack Web Development from Udacity. Skilled in Python, JavaScript, Data Analytics, Front End Development, Web Applications, Critical Thinking, and Databases. Strong engineering professional pursuing a Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.) focused in Computer Engineering from Sardar Vallabhbhai National Institute of Technology, Surat. Also, pursuing a Nanodegree in Data Analysis.

Skills & Expertise

- Python
- Data Analysis
- Web Applications
- Numpy
- Web Frameworks
- Database Design
- Vagrant
- Public Speaking
- Backbone.js, ReactJS, AngularJS
- Github
- Google Cloud
- Intro to Machine Learning

- HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap
- JavaScript
- Pandas
- Responsive Applications
- Relational Databases
- Web Servers
- Critical Thinking
- Flask & Django
- Jupyter Notebook
- Google App Engine
- Google Maps API
- Data Structures

Work Experience

Chief Technical Officer at Aroma Remedies & Cadenza Group (May 2017 – Present)

- Building software solutions such as Enterprise Resource Planning software.
- Preparing and updating fully responsive websites.
- Digitalizing filing & documenting system for the companies.

Organizer & Mentor at Google Developers Group, Surat

(July 2016 - Present)

- Community of developers at NIT, Surat.
- Working on the ideology of learning, creating & sharing your knowledge.
- Getting exposure to new Web Development advances.
- Mentoring juniors in determining career paths as developers.
- Contributions in building projects for the community.

Education

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Computer Engineering

National Institute of Technology Surat, (2015 – Currently)

Nanodegree in Data Analytics (In Process)

Udacity (June, 2017)

Nanodegree in Full Stack Web Development

Udacity (February, 2017)

Activities: A series of Web Development Projects, along with career development courses.

Undergraduate - Science

Coast Guard Public School Daman (May, 2015)

Projects

1. IGNIS Website (February, 2017)

Link: http://ignis.org.in/

Members: Apurva Tripathi, Abhishek Svnit

- Website for the Annual sports meet of SVNIT.
- Contribution in making the website fully responsive.
- Significant work in building UI more attractive.

2. SVNIT Map (January, 2017)

Link: https://aptr13.github.io/SVNIT-Map/

Members: Apurva Tripathi

- A neighborhood map project built using multiple APIs.
- Detailed information about each building and monument around SVNIT campus.
- Built using backbone.js framework and JSON datastore.
- Getting hands on with the MVC concept of JS frameworks.

3. TV Series App (December, 2016)

Link: https://github.com/ApTr13/TV-Series-App

Members: Apurva Tripathi

- A catalog application displaying all your favorite TV Series
- Along with their Star cast, description and list of all their episodes.
- Built upon Flask framework, using Postgresql database.
- Understanding ease of creating Apps using powerful Python frameworks.

Certifications

Full Stack Web Developer Nanodegree

Link: http://aptr13.me/img/fsnd.jpg

Udacity (February, 2017)

Volunteer Experience

Coordinator

Joyfest, SVNIT (January, 2016 – Present)

A student level social organization that performs Social Services around the city of Surat.